Guide to the Edwin Hoyt Lockwood Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Edwin Hoyt Lockwood papers
1890-1932
MS 328
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
0.75
(2 boxes)
The papers consist of a series of automobile chassis dynamometer tests conducted at Yale (1916-1932) by Edwin Hoyt Lockwood and material relating to the performance of early automobiles.
Lockwood, Edwin Hoyt
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The papers were given by the Department of Engineering and Applied Sciences in 1965.
Scope and Contents
The papers of Edwin Hoyt Lockwood (1866-1930) are contained in two manuscript boxes, one of automobile chassis dynamometer tests and an explanation of the methods used and calibration calculations, and one containing a laboratory experiment notebook kept in 1893.
The body of this collection is a series of automobile chassis dynamometer tests which Lockwood and his students performed from 1916-1931. Virtually all the great classic cars are represented even though the collection is not complete. Professor Lockwood numbered the series of tests 100-435, but this collection contains only approximately 200 of the 345 original tests. These are blueprint copies of the original test information. The originals of the series were deposited in the Ford Museum, Dearborn, Michigan. Along with the copies of the original tests is an explanation of the testing methods and calculations used in calibrating the measuring equipment.
There are also two studies of independent engineering problems: a calculation of the Frequency of A Mallable Iron Fittings Company, (Branford, Conn.) Vibrator and the correspondence concerning the problem, and a study of Centrifugal Force and Coiled Springs.
Biographical / Historical
Edwin Hoyt Lockwood was born October 31, 1866, in New Canaan, Connecticut. He prepared for Yale at the New Canaan Seminary and received his Ph.B. from Sheffield Scientific School in 1888. He continued to be associated with the scientific divisions of Yale until his death. He received his M.E. in 1892 and his Ph.D. in 1901. He began as an instructor in the Department of Mechanical Engineering and continued in that department steadily rising in rank until he was appointed Robert Higgins Professor of Mechanical Engineering in 1927. He was a member of the American Society of Engineers, The Society of Automotive Engineers, the Society of Mechanical Heating and Ventilating Engineers, The American Academy of Arts and Sciences, and other engineering societies. He contributed articles to The Journal of Automotive Engineers, Power, The Scientific American, and the Yale Alumni Weekly. He also wrote a pamphlet on mechanical drawing (Tuttle, Morehouse, and Taylor, 1892), and contributed a chapter on perspective to John Clayton Tracy's Introductory Course in Mechanical Drawing(New York, 1898).
His real reputation came not from mechanical drawing, but from the development of experimental mechanical and automotive engineering in which he played a part. He came to be respected as the leading authority in the scientific aspects of automotive design and testing, and in the late 1920's performed automotive tests on new models for the companies which produced them. His tests were as authoritative as the road tests conducted by independent testing companies today, in the days before road tests became standard.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Automobiles -- Design and construction; Engineering; Europe; Germany; Blueprints; Engineers; Lockwood, Edwin Hoyt; Yale University -- Faculty; Yale University. Sheffield Scientific School
- Inventory
  Scope and Contents
  Note: Series No. with an asterisk indicates that the make and model are known, but the test material is missing from this collection. These and the blank entries should be found at the Ford Museum in Dearborn, Michigan, where the original test material was deposited by Professor Lockwood.
  - Study of Mallable Iron Fittings Company (Branford, Conn.) Vibrator (Box 1)
  - Study of Centrifugal Force and Coiled Springs (Box 1)
  - Explanation of Automobile Chassis Dynamometer Testing Methods (Box 1)
  - Test Series Calibration Calculations (Box 1)
  - Automobile Chassis Dynamometer Tests
    - Series No. 100: Chalmers, 6-30, 1916 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 101: Packard, Phaeton (2-25), 1916 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 102: Franklin, Series 9, 1916 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 103: Overland, Model 42, 1911 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 104 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 105 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 106 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 107: Franklin, Series 9, 1917 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 108: Buick, D55, 1916 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 109: National, Series A-B, 1916 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 110 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 111 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 112: Marmon, Touring Model 34, 1916 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 113 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 114: Oldsmobile, Model 45, 1917 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 115: Oldsmobile, Model 45, 1917 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 116*: Oldsmobile (Box 1)
    - Series No. 117 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 118 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 119 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 120 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 121: GMC Truck, Model 16, 1918 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 121A: GMC Truck, Model 16, 1918 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 122*: Fiat (Box 1)
    - Series No. 123: Jeffrey, 1917 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 124: Ford, Model "T", 1917 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 125A: Hudson, 6-40 Model "G", 1916 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 126: Hudson, Super Six Model "J", 1917 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 127 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 128: Packard, 2-35, 1917 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 129 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 130: Overland, Model 85, 1916 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 131 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 132: Crane-Simplex, 1916 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 133: Stanley Steamer, Model 726, 1916 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 134 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 135: Stanley Steamer, Model 735, 1918 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 136: Franklin, Series 5, 1914 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 137*: Overland (Box 1)
    - Series No. 138: Franklin, Series 9B, 1919 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 139*: Overland (Box 1)
    - Series No. 140: Buick, D-45, 1917 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 141: Overland, Model 85, 1917 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 142: Fiat, 50-56, 1913 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 143: Overland, Coupe, 85-6, 1917 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 144 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 145 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 146: Maxwell, Model 25, 1919 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 147: Marmon, Model 34, 1917 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 148: Stutz, Series 4-6, 1919 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 149: Mercer, "Raceabout", 1917 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 150: Cadillac, Convertible Victoria, 1918 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 151: Studebaker, SF 4-40, 1918 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 152: Ford, Touring, 1917 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 153: Overland, Model 81, 1915 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 154: Oldsmobile, Model 45-A, 1919 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 155: Oldsmobile, Model 45-A, 1919 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 156: Oldsmobile, Model 45, 1919 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 157: Peerless, 7 Pass. Touring, 1916 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 158: Stevens, Salient Six, Model 84, 1919 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 159: Oldsmobile, Truck (¾ Ton), 1919 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 160: Stephens, Salient Six, Model 86, 1919 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 161: Stephens, Salient Six, Model 84, 1919 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 162: Oldsmobile, Touring, Model 45B, 1919 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 163: Oldsmobile, Model 37, 1919 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 164: Cadillac, Model 55, 1915 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 165*: Franklin (Box 1)
    - Series No. 166: Paige, 1915 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 167: Ford, Model "T", 1918 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 168: White, Model "GAF", 1913 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 169: Hupmobile, Model "N", 1916 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 170 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 171: Overland, Model 85-6, 1917 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 172: Duplex, 1½ Ton Truck, 1920 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 173: White, Model "GAF", 1913 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 174: Buick, Model 21-Six-45, 1921 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 175: Packard, Twin Six, 1921 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 176: Mercer, Series 5, 1920 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 177: GMC, K-16 Truck (¾ Ton), 1920 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 178 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 179: Chevrolet, 440, 1921 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 180 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 181: Chevrolet, Model "T", 1 Ton Truck, 1921 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 182: Ford, Model "T", 1921 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 183: Stanley Steamer, 1918 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 184: Packard, Sedan 2-25, 1916 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 185: Kissel, 1918 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 186: Kissel, 6-42, 1916 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 187: Dodge, Touring, 1915 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 188 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 189: Buick, Roadster, K-6-44, 1920 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 190: Mercedes, Touring, 1909 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 191: Studebaker, EG, 1921 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 192: Lincoln, 1921 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 193: Pierce Arrow, 6-48, 1920 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 194*: Locomobile (Box 1)
    - Series No. 195: Stutz, Model "H", 1920 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 196: Cole 8, Touring, 1921 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 197: Stutz, Model "H", 1920 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 198: Reo, Speed Wagon, 1919 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 199: Essex, Model "A", 1919 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 200: U.S. Army Truck, Standardized "B", Second Series, 1921 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 201: U.S. Army Truck, Standardized "B", Second Series, 1921 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 202: Detroit, Trailer Truck (3 Ton), 1921 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 203: White, Army Reconnaisance, 1918 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 204: Mack, AC 7½ Ton Truck, 1921 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 205: U.S. Army Truck, Standardized "B", Second Series, 1921 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 206 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 207*: Reo (Box 1)
    - Series No. 208: White, Model "GAF", 1913 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 209 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 210: Franklin, Series 9B, 1922 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 211: McFarlan, Brougham, 1922 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 212: Cleveland, Model 6, 1922 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 213*: Chandler (Box 1)
    - Series No. 214: Haynes, "55", 1922 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 215*: Overland (Box 1)
    - Series No. 216*: Ford (Box 1)
    - Series No. 217: Willys-Knight, Model 20, 1922 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 218*: Mercer (Box 1)
    - Series No. 219: Wills Sainte Claire, 1922 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 220: Franklin, Series 9, 1917 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 221*: Studebaker (Box 1)
    - Series No. 222: Buick, K45, 1920 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 223: Maxwell, Model 25, 1922 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 224A: McFarlan, Model 145, 1922 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 225: Cunningham, "8", 1916 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 226*: Dodge (Box 1)
    - Series No. 227*: Overland (Box 1)
    - Series No. 228*: Packard 6 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 229*: Locomobile (Box 1)
    - Series No. 230 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 231 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 232 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 233*: Reo (Box 1)
    - Series No. 234*: Ford (Box 1)
    - Series No. 235: Ford, Model "T", Runabout, 1922 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 236*: Maxwell (Box 1)
    - Series No. 237*: Maxwell (Box 1)
    - Series No. 238*: Ford, Sedan (Box 1)
    - Series No. 239 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 240: Ford, Model "T", Touring, 1922 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 241: Willys-Knight, Model 20A, 1923 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 242 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 243: Overland, Model 85-A, 1923 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 244: Buick, K-44, 1920 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 245*: Chevrolet (Box 1)
    - Series No. 246*: Durant (Box 1)
    - Series No. 247*: Star (Box 1)
    - Series No. 248: Essex, 1923 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 249: Hudson, Super-Six, 1922 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 250*: Franklin (Box 1)
    - Series No. 251: Mercer, Series V, 1922 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 252: Mitchell, F-50, 1923 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 253: Gardner, Model 4, 1922 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 254*: Pierce-Arrow (Box 1)
    - Series No. 255: Packard, Single Six, 1920 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 256: Willys-Knight, 20A, 1922 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 257*: Buick Six (Box 1)
    - Series No. 258: Franklin, Series 10B, 1923 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 259: Cole, 870, 1919 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 260*: Ford (Box 1)
    - Series No. 261*: Ford (Box 1)
    - Series No. 262 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 263*: Packard 12 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 264*: Studebaker (Box 1)
    - Series No. 265 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 266: Lexington, Model 23, 1923 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 267: Rickenbacker, Series "A", 1923 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 268: Oldsmobile "4", 43A, 1923 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 269: Buick, G-45, 1923 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 270*: Chandler (Box 1)
    - Series No. 271: Cunningham, 1919V (Box 1)
    - Series No. 272*: Stutz (Box 1)
    - Series No. 273*: Mercer (Box 1)
    - Series No. 274*: Studebaker (Box 1)
    - Series No. 275*: Packard (Box 1)
    - Series No. 276*: Bessemer Truck, Model "L", 2½-3 Ton, 1923 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 277*: Overland (Box 1)
    - Series No. 278*: Studebaker (Box 1)
    - Series No. 279: Buick, 24-Four-35, 1924 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 280: Knox, Touring, 1912 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 281: H.C.S., Series IV, Model 6, 1923 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 282: Dort, Model 27, 1924 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 283*: Flint (Box 1)
    - Series No. 284*: Peerless (Box 1)
    - Series No. 285*: Dodge (Box 1)
    - Series No. 286*: Ford, Sedan (Box 1)
    - Series No. 287: Studebaker, Special Six, 1921 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 288: Stutz, "G", 1919 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 289: Gardner, Series 5, Model "C", 1924 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 290: Franklin, Series 10B, 1924 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 291: Franklin, Series 11, 1924 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 292: Essex, 1924 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 293: Mercedes, Model 28/95, 1924 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 294*: Marmon (Box 1)
    - Series No. 295: Chrysler, 1924 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 296: Buick, 22-44, 1922 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 297: Packard, Sport Model, 1924 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 298: Indian Motor Cycle, 1924 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 299: Harley-Davidson Cycle, 74 cu. in. (Box 1)
    - Series No. 300: Harley-Davidson Cycle, 1923 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 301*: Isotta-Frasclini (Box 1)
    - Series No. 302*: Flint (Box 1)
    - Series No. 303: Packard, 7 Pass. Touring, 1924 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 304*: Ford (Box 1)
    - Series No. 305*: Chrysler (Box 1)
    - Series No. 306: Buick, Standard Six, 25-25, 1925 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 307*: Buick (Box 1)
    - Series No. 308: Buick, 25-35, 1923 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 309A*: Cadillac, V-63 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 310*: Pierce-Arrow, "80" (Box 1)
    - Series No. 311*: Lincoln (Box 1)
    - Series No. 312*: Premier (Box 1)
    - Series No. 313*: Jordan (Box 1)
    - Series No. 314A*: Packard 8 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 314B*: Packard 8 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 315*: Buick (Box 1)
    - Series No. 316*: Chrysler (Box 1)
    - Series No. 317*: Buick, Roadmaster "6" (Box 1)
    - Series No. 318*: Buick, Roadmaster "6" (Box 1)
    - Series No. 319*: Ford (Box 1)
    - Series No. 320*: Franklin (Box 1)
    - Series No. 321*: Oldsmobile "6" (Box 1)
    - Series No. 322*: Maxwell (Box 1)
    - Series No. 323*: Pierce-Arrow (Box 1)
    - Series No. 324*: Dort (Box 1)
    - Series No. 325: Mercedes, 24-100-14-, 1925 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 326*: Chevrolet (Box 1)
    - Series No. 327*: Franklin (Box 1)
    - Series No. 328*: Mercedes (Box 1)
    - Series No. 329*: Chrysler (Box 1)
    - Series No. 330*: Chrysler (Box 1)
    - Series No. 331*: Chrysler (Box 1)
    - Series No. 332*: Wills Sainte Claire (Box 1)
    - Series No. 333*: Chrysler (Box 1)
    - Series No. 334*: Buick, Standard Six (Box 1)
    - Series No. 335 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 336 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 337 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 338 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 339 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 340 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 341 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 342 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 343 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 344 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 345 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 346 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 347*: Cunningham (Box 1)
    - Series No. 348 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 349: Harley-Davidson Motorcycle, 74 cu. in.; 25-JDCB-2748, 1925 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 350*: Harley-Davidson Motorcycle, 61 cu. in. (Box 1)
    - Series No. 351*: Harley-Davidson Motorcycle, 21 cu. in. (Box 1)
    - Series No. 352 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 353*: Harley-Davidson Motorcycle, 74 cu. in. (Box 1)
    - Series No. 354*: Studebaker, Standard Six (Box 1)
    - Series No. 355 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 356*: Chrysler, "80" (Box 1)
    - Series No. 357*: Indian Motorcycle, 21 cu. in. (Box 1)
    - Series No. 358*: Nash (Box 1)
    - Series No. 359: Buick, Standard Six, Series 115, 1927 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 360: Buick, Standard Six, Series 115, 1927 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 361 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 362*: Buick, Standard Six (Box 1)
    - Series No. 363*: Ford (Box 1)
    - Series No. 364: Chrysler, "80", 1926 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 364A: Chrysler, "80", 1926 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 365: Willys-Knight, 6-66 (Great Six), 1927 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 366: Cadillac, V-63, 1927 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 367: Lincoln, Phaeton, 1926 (Box 1)
  - Series No. 368*: LaSalle
    - Series No. 369: Reo Flying Cloud, Model "A", 1927 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 370A: Nash, Special Six, Model 340, 1927 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 371: Reo Flying Cloud, Model "A", 1927 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 372 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 373A: LaSalle, Town Sedan, 1927 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 373B: LaSalle, Town Sedan, 1927 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 374: Packard, Sedan, 526, 1928 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 375: Studebaker, Commander, 1927 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 376: Buick, Standard Six Sedan, 1925 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 377*: Studebaker (Box 1)
    - Series No. 378*: Chrysler, "72" (Box 1)
    - Series No. 379*: Franklin, Air Man (Box 1)
    - Series No. 380*: Packard, "8" Special (Box 1)
    - Series No. 381: Reo, Wolverine Brougham, Model "B", 1928 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 382*: Stutz, 8 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 383: Buick, Master Six, Touring, 1928 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 384: Hudson, Super Six Coach, 1928 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 385: Marmon, 8 Sedan, 1927 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 386*: Packard, Standard Eight (Box 1)
    - Series No. 387: Packaard, Special Eight Sedan, 1928 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 388*: Essex, Super Six (Box 1)
    - Series No. 389*: Buick, Master Six (Box 1)
    - Series No. 390: Cadillac, Convertible Coupe, 1928 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 391*: Ford, Model "A" (Box 1)
    - Series No. 392*: Whippet 4 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 393: Oldsmobile, F-28, 1928 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 394: Nash, "470", 1929 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 395: Buick, Coupe, 1928 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 396A: Oakland, AA Roadster, 1928 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 396B: Oakland, AA Roadster, 1928 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 397: Buick, 28-55, 1928 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 398*: Chevrolet (Box 1)
    - Series No. 399: Cadillac, V-57, Touring, 1929 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 400: Nash, "425", 1929 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 401: Packard, Standard Eight Sedan, Model 626, 1929 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 402: Cadillac, V-57, Touring, 1929 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 403: Hupmobile, Century Six Sedan, 1928 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 404: Chrysler, Model 75 Roadster, 1929 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 405: Franklin, 5 Passenger Sedan, 1929 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 406*: Chevrolet (Box 1)
    - Series No. 407 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 408: Rolls-Royce, Phantom Sedan, 1929 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 409*: Packard (Box 1)
    - Series No. 410*: Minerva (Box 1)
    - Series No. 411*: Packard (Box 1)
    - Series No. 412*: Cadillac (Box 1)
    - Series No. 413*: Chrysler (Box 1)
    - Series No. 414*: Cadillac (Box 1)
    - Series No. 415*: DeSoto (Box 1)
    - Series No. 416*: Franklin (Box 1)
    - Series No. 417 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 418: Buick, Model 29-58, 1929 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 419: Stutz, Convertible Sedan, 1929 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 420: Chrysler, "77", 1930 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 421*: Chrysler (Box 1)
    - Series No. 422*: Hupmobile 8 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 423*: Studebaker 8 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 424*: Packard, "633" (Box 1)
    - Series No. 425: Lincoln, Sedan, 1930 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 426*: Oakland (Box 1)
    - Series No. 427*: LaSalle, 1930 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 428*: Cadillac, V-12 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 429: Ford, Model "A", 1930 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 430*: Buick 8 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 431*: Buick 8 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 432*: LaSalle, 1930 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 433: Willys, Six Roadster, 97-A, 1931 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 434*: Ford, Model "A" (Box 1)
    - Series No. 435*: Chevrolet 6, 1932 (Box 1)
    - Series No. 436*: Miller Racing Car (Box 1)
  - Notebook of laboratory work kept by Lockwood, 1893 (Box 2)
  - Lecture notes for his "Freshman Drawing, 1890. List of plates with a description of each.": 1 vol., 50 pp. 1896, New Haven. Manuscript. (Box 2)
  - Lecture notes for his "Course in Mechanical Drawing. Freshman Class, 1891.": 2 vols., 50 pp. 1891, New Haven. Manuscript. (Box 2)